Guide to the Emma Koberg, collector, letters,1822-1852.
Koberg, Emma collector, letters,1822-1852.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Emma Koberg, collector, letters, 1822-1852.
6001
Emma Koberg, collector
1 reel microfilm.
Letters.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Forty-one letters concerning the Sons of Temperance, religious activities, legal actions, family matters, 1848 Democratic State Convention, a Revolutionary War widow's pension, a petition for a government post for a physician, and complaints about a bequest. Correspondents include John F. Graham, Jno. H. Redington, Aaron Vanderpool, and Erastus Corning.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Forty-one letters concerning the Sons of Temperance, religious activities, legal actions, family matters, 1848 Democratic State Convention, a Revolutionary War widow's pension, a petition for a government post for a physician, and complaints about a bequest. Correspondents include John F. Graham, Jno. H. Redington, Aaron Vanderpool, and Erastus Corning.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Koberg, Emma,; Corning, Erastus; Graham, John F.; Redington, Jno. H.; Vanderpool, Aaron.; Democratic Party (U.S.); Sons of Temperance of North America.
Subjects:
Temperance--New York (State); Family--New York (State)--Ontario County; Family--New York (State)--Wayne County.; Military pensions.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Letters
  - From A.B. Clemons, D,G,W,P. (Palmyra N.Y.) to John F. Graham, G.W.P. (Geneva N.Y.)., December 4, 1847; 1
    Discusses the growth of the Wayne Division of the Sons of Temperance and current activities of both the Wayne and Palmyra groups.
  - From Hiram Schur, M.P. (Port Gibson N.Y.) to John F. Graham G.W.P. (Geneva N.Y.)., June 6, 1848; 2
    Asks for information concerning a Sons of Temperance member whose position in the local government required him to rule on granting liquor licenses. Brother James Halladay Esq. has been charged with violating his obligation since he granted a license.
  - A Prohibition leaflet stating "The Saloon Must Go" copyright W. Brown., 1888; 3
  - From A.B. Lucing (Philipsville N.Y.) to John F. Graham (Geneva N.Y.)., September 11, 1868; 4
    Letter discusses whether it is amenable to the Sons of Temperance Constitution that a member be granted a license to retail liquor.
  - From H. Boynton and J.A. Murry with a post script from J. Smith (Red Creek N.Y. to Rev. P.A. Murry (Geneva N.Y.)., December 15, 1842; 5
    Describes a revival in Red Creek lasting 3-4 weeks where the authors have labored with the assistance of Bros. Tonisley and C. Smith.
  - From Jno. H. Redington (Auburn N.Y.) to Jedediah Burchard (Evangelist) (Springfield, Windsor Co., Vermont), November 27, 1834; 6
    Redington encourages Burchard to be a true Christian, talks about Burchard's wife, and requests prayers for "a serious student of theology and a true minister," i.e. himself.
  - From ____ Armitage (Jefferson) to John F. Graham G.W.P. (Geneva), March 8, 1849; 7
    Concerns an application to the Grand Temple at N.Y. City for the charter of a temple to be located in Jefferson and called "Salubrin Temple." The author requests that Graham write a letter of recommendation. He reports that two divisions have been formed from his: one at Townsend's settlement, one at Reading Centre. Another is to be formed at Burdette.
  - From Alvah Nash (Havanah N.Y.) to Dr. John F. Graham (Geneva N.Y.)., February 10, 1848; 8
    The brothers have been directed to sing those tunes at the opening and closing initiation which are in the book. They protest and argue that they should have the privilege of singing what they see fit. Please advise.
  - From Alvah Nash to John F. Graham (Geneva N.Y.)., February 28, 1848; 9
    Inquires whether the brothers may withdraw without permission or may send in their card. Past D.D.S.P.S. B. Denton has done the latter.
  - From G.H. Crane (Clarkson Village) to J.F. Graham (Geneva N.Y.)., No date; 10
    Application for a division, proceedings of the organization of a division, and a fee of $6.00, Gives a list of officers. He talks of the high cost of supporting temperance work and wishes he had more support so he could attend the Grand Division Meeting next month.
  - From William Gibson, Attorney (Lyons N.Y.) to Francis Bloodgood, Esq., Clerk of the Superior Court of N.Y. (Albany)., December 9, 1822; 11
    Requests a court hearing in Ja. for his client, John Clofs, vs. Henry Garlock.
  - From William Sipin (Gibson?), Attorney (Lyons N.Y.) to Francis Bloodgood, Esq. Clerk of the Superior Court (Albany)., December 12, 1822; 12
    Requests that a notice for argument on demurrer for William Hough be placed on the dockett. From W.J. Hough re. May Je 1822, Dec. 16, 1822.
  - From Mrs. Elizabeth Hawkins (South Windsor, Broome Co., N.Y.) to W.J. Hough (N.P.)., December 21, 1822; 13
    A family letter with a poem "to Mother" at the end.
  - From Lafayette Craw (South Butler N.Y.) to Mesrs. Hubbal & Curran (Utica N.Y.)., July 26, 1849; 14
    This letter requests a large list of items desired for purchase and requests a bill for past purchases. (Talks of stock for a store paid for with kips (undressed hides).
  - From Chas. W. Torrey (Walworth N.Y.) to Mr. E.B. Walsworth, Union College, Schenectady N.Y., September 1848; 15
    Family letter with a p.s. from Walworth's sister Jane.
  - To Hiram D. Vosburgh No. 17 Lancaster St., Albany N.Y. Return: West Meadow St. Discusses weather, son's health, money, farm crops. From S. Vosburgh to her son, (Macedon), Oct. 27.1888; 16
  - Not Listed, 17
  - From Joseph Moody (Junius) to M. Hoffman, Esq. Attorney at Law, October 18, 1822; 18
    Requesting legal advice.
  - Edward Stewart attorney for William Pierpont to Francis Bloodgood, Esq. Clerk of the Superior Court in Albany requesting a Court space., July 27, 1822; 19
  - From John R. Gaiton (Walcott N.Y.) to Mr. Charles (Gainton), (Sheldon MA)., October 29, 18[31 or 44]; 20
    Requests that Gainton examine himself.
  - Diary Notations. Charles M. Gainton, April 3, 1834. Almost 44 years have joined those before since I wrote the above in our house in Shelburne, Massachusetts. Glastonbury, Conn., March 11, 1878; 21
  - From C. Foster, Sheriff (Palmyra N.Y.) to A. Vanderpool, Esq., Counselor at Law (Kinderhook N.Y.), July 16, 1829-; 22
    Foster has served copies on Jonathon Sheldon. He says Fitch must pay the demand.
  - Envelope to Miss Euphenia Giver (Honoye Falls, Monroe Co., N.Y.) from Savanagh, dated July 14; 23
  - From Sam E. Hudson (Palmyra N.Y.) to Aaron Vanderpool, Esq. and Tolicy (Kinderhook N.Y.)., June 11, 1835; 24
    Hudson requests advice from Hudson on various legal matters.
  - Env. from Mother Vosburgh (Macedon N.Y.) to her son Hiram D. Vosburgh (no. 17 Lancaster St. Albany)., No date; 25
    Inquiring after her son's health since a recent trip home gave him a cold. Also, a note from Ewy.
  - From Thos. Amrstrong (Butler N.Y.) to Hon. Erastus Coming (AIM M.)., February 12, 1848; 26
    Acknowledges receipt of a note informing Corning that he was designated as the Democratic Candidate for Presidential Elector for the 27th district by the Democratic State Convention held at the capital on the 26th and
  - From William J. Boton (Red Creek N.Y.) to Young Lewis Esq. (Lenox, Madison Co., N.Y.)., December 30, 1863; 27
    Offering to undertake obtaining a pension for Widow Barnette if she was married prior to 1794.
  - From A.L. Beaumont (Lyons N.Y.) to Arron Van Derpoil Esq. Councellor at Law (Kinderhook Co. N.Y.)., December 30, 1863; 28
    Instructing his solicitor as to how to collect debts.
  - From Gad Hall (Huron) to Mr. Johan Knox (Augusta, Oneida Co.), September 26, 1836; 29
    . Requests that Mr. Knox collect some notes for him.
  - From George W. Guyler (Phelps N.Y.) to Col. Elias Cost, Postmaster (Oaks Comers), his uncle, n.d.; 30
    Comments on the election of Martin Van Buren
  - To Mr. William Pako (Friendship, Alleghany N.Y.)., May 12, 1844; 31
    From his brother (Waterloo) informing of their father's death.
  - G.W. Pum Furmie (Waterloo N.Y.) to D. Thompson, New York., January 2, 1847; 32
    -Please endorse the above to Jeremiah Apdykes account.
  - From Asa Chamberlain (Ovid N.Y.) to Mr. Wm. S. Holt (Norfolk, St. Lawrence Co., N.Y.), July 17, 1839; 33
    - Asa reports on his trip to Ovid to look at farms to buy. He gives his appraisal of the area and gives directions on how to get there by canal.
  - M.G. Hoyt (Waterloo N.Y.) to Wm. S. Stow, Esq. Counselor at Law (Clyde N.Y.)., October 21, 1845; 34
    As the case of the Waterloo Baptist Society cannot be tried this week in the absence of Dr. Richardson, and as the Election is close at hand, perhaps it is advisable to put it off.
  - Envelope from S.A. Goodwin to Stephen A. Goodwin Esq. (Auburn, N.Y.)., October 31, 1844; 35
  - From someone (Auburn N.Y.) to Wm. S. Stow Esq. of Clyde N.Y., dated October 30, 1844; 36
    Re: legal matters.
  - From Z. Reeves (Palmyra N.Y.) to George W. Newell Esq. (Albany N.Y.)., February 17, 1834; 37
    The author thanks Newell for informing him of a "petition against the Superintendent of the Western Section Erie Canal" and asks to be kept informed of other documents relating to his official station.
  - From Wm. V. Douglas and Catherine Douglas (Covert N.Y.) to Mrs. Margaret A. Kidd (Geneva N.Y.)., February 3, 1839; 38
    Discusses birth of a daughter, a boarder, a visitor, and other family news. Note Mr. A. Ledd, Helen Ledd. (Notes missing from Delia and Douglass).
  - From W. Smith (Farmer N.Y., Seneca Co.) to H.D. Barto (Trumansburg)., March 1831; 39
    In reply to Barto, Smith discusses the situation with some notes he holds.
  - Letter from 5 citizens of Junius to Hon. Robert S. Rose,: in Congress Wash., D.C., January 19, 1824; 40
    Recommends Dr. George B. Eliot of Waterloo for appointment in the army since his services in the last war damaged his health and left him unable to practice in the country. Signed John Rose, Barker, Rhoad, Birdsall and Birdsall. Enclosed is a letter from Elliot requesting a permanent station in a Northern post. From George F. Bush (Junius N.Y.) to A.J. Winch (Cando).
  - To George Bush (Canandaigua N.Y., Ontario Co.)., June 29, 1831; 41
    Complains about being left only $50 out of his father's large estate, and his health. Also complains about his sister Cassie's small bequest of $50 so she doesn't have anything to live on in her old age.